Modern [defn]PSY > psychology[/defn] has a word that is probably used more
نحن نذهب لتغيير الطريقة التي يفكر بها العالم حول الموارد الطبيعية
than any other word in psychology.
من أي كلمة أخرى في علم النفس.
It is a word "maladjusted".
هو كلمة "غير منسجم".
This is the ringing cry of modern child psychology.
هذا هو صرخة من رنين علم نفس الطفل الحديث.
Maladjusted
غير منسجم
Now, of course we all want to live the well adjusted life
الآن، بالطبع نحن جميعا نريد أن نعيش حياة جيدة تعديلها
in order to avoid neurotic and schizophrenic personalities.
من أجل تجنب العصبية و انفصام  شخصيات
As I moved towards my conclusion
كما انتقلت نحو استنتاج
I would like to say to you today in very honest manner,
وأود أن أقول لكم اليوم بطريقة صادقة جدا،
there´re some things in our [defn]SOC > society[/defn] and some things in our world
هناك بعض الأشياء في مجتمعنا، وبعض الأشياء في عالمنا
which I´m proud to be maladjusted.
أنا فخور أن يكون غير منسجم.
And I call upon all men of good will
وإنني أدعو جميع ذوي النوايا الحسنة
to be maladjusted to these things
أن يكون غير منسجم لهذه الأمور
until the good society´s realized.
حتى المجتمع الجيد تحقق من ذلك
I must honestly say to you that I never intend to adjust myself
لا بد لي  و بصراحة   أن أقول  لكم انني لم تنوي تكيف نفسي
to racial segregation and [defn]DISC > discrimination[/defn].
إلى التفرقة العنصرية والتمييز
I never intend to adjust myself to religious bigotry.
أنا لا تنوي تكيف نفسي للتعصب الديني
I never intend to adjust myself to economic conditions
أنا لا نوي تعديل نفسي للظروف الاقتصادية
that will take necessities from the many to give luxuries to the few,
سوف تأخذ من الضروريات لاعطاء العديد من الكماليات للاقلية
leave millions of God´s children smothering
ترك الملايين من اختناق الاطفال
in an air-tight cage of poverty in the midst of an affluent society.
في قفص محكمة الغلق من الفقر في خضم مجتمع رغد الحياة